so I'm getting a lot of questions uh
with the 2 by the people who bought 2x4
asking about how do you choose your
maximum loading and the the submaximum
loading was pretty straightforward
you're just going to go three sets of
one to five reps depending on the week
with between 60 and 80% of one rep
max that's for the technique work uh
with submaximum loading but for the
maximum loading I was kind of V
and so I wanted to film a video and
explain this it's very hard for me to
say you know do three sets of five with
85% your one rep max or three sets of
three with 90% percentages as I as I
explained this in the book percentages
don't work for everyone maybe six out of
10 people it'll be perfect for them but
the other four people it'll be either
too heavy or too light some people it'll
be impossible and some people it'll be
so easy they don't get training effect
so you have to figure this out uh and
and it probably has a lot to do with the
composition of fast twitch versus slow
twitch muscle fibers but there are other
factors as well so I can you know while
I could probably you can use rep
calculators that are available online to
to give you General estimates remember
you're repeating the first six weeks of
the program you're repeating this for
three sets so it's not what you can get
for one set of five it's what you can
get for three sets of five
and the other thing is you can't just
base it off your one rep max you can't
initially but keep in mind um if you're
like myself and Andrew and the other
people who did the program you'll be
getting stronger so you you you'd have
to readjust Without Really knowing what
what's happening with your one rep max
you just kind of know that you're
gaining strength with the program for
example you know when I did the block
pull the first time I did it I wasn't as
experienced with it but throughout the
the 14 weeks program I got a lot better
and more coordinated at the Block pull
so my strength went way up so by the end
when I did my maximal set of you know my
maximal single or my a sing sets I was
doing way heavier weight than when I
initially
started but anyway here's how you can go
about it let's say you're on week one
and you're doing the squat or the bench
press or something like that and you
want to determine your three sets of
five Max
so maybe you you're going to do your
Dynamic warm-up and then maybe you're
going to do you know the bar for 10 reps
then you throw on a 45lb plate you do
135 for five reps then you throw on a 25
on each side you do 185 for five reps
it's easy take the 25s off put a 45 on
each side now you're at 225 lbs you do
five reps and it's pretty hard it's not
you know you know you could probably get
get it for like
eight uh but that's pretty close so then
you're you say okay I need to get three
sets of five I know I could get it with
225 but I don't quite think I could get
it with 245 lbs so I'm going to put a
five on each side and have
235 and then I'm going to go for three
sets of five with that
weight and uh and you know hopefully
you'll get it if I recommend just
sticking to the rep scheme if you went
too heavy and you only got say you got
five on the first set five on the second
set and then three or four on the third
set well then what I would do there is
just kind of you can just make a note of
it or just say you know you know you
could have gotten you went 235 you know
if you would have done 230 lbs you would
have gotten it so I would just kind of
lie and just write on the record on the
pr sheet 230 lbs and that way next time
you know to try and beat that next time
around you want to go for 235 or
something like that when you repeat 2x4
but uh let's say you do the three sets
of five and it's pretty easy well you
have the option of repping out on that
third set say you get five then five and
then on the third set you get seven or
eight but keep in mind that you're
training four days per week on this
program and you know couple days later
you might have to hit a deadlift a heavy
deadlift or something like that so you
don't want to totally you know um you
don't want to over tax yourself keep in
mind this is an accumulating program six
weeks on then a D Lo then six weeks on
and then another D Lo week so um I hope
that sheds some light on how to choose
the
PRS uh you just kind of use use your
knowledge of Prior lifting to kind of
guesstimate use warm-up sets and then at
the end of the day it's just a a guess
but what's nice is the first time my
first time running
2x4 I I was I've always been really good
at you know figuring out what loads to
use so I I felt all my PRS were very
challenging but my second time around
that's when I feel like I gained even
more strength because um then I had
pretty challenging PRS that I had to
beat so you know I had you know you know
when when when you're going for my I
think my deadlift uh you know three
singles was like 515 for three singles
and I've got to beat that so that's
pretty daunting but I did it the second
time around and I think you see better
results the second time around when you
re repeat 2x4 so I recommend doing it
either twice back to back or you could
spread it out do the 14we program wait a
couple months do it again but I do
recommend you do it two to three times a
year and you keep that you'll have that
PR sheet so what's nice is that the next
time you repeat it you can look at your
tracker sheet and say okay here's what I
need to beat and you will find that you
do beat it but also bear in mind as I
said earlier you will be gaining
strength so you can't just go by
percentages before you start the program
because they will be scaling upwards
throughout the
program last thing to keep in mind the
first six weeks you're doing uh straight
sets so three sets of five with the same
load three sets of three with the same
load three sets of one with the same
load then you take a D Lo week and then
the next six weeks are asending sets
meaning you're really just working your
way up to a top set so a maximal set of
five a maximal set of three a maximal
single and what you'll find is you can
generally do you know depending on your
stength maybe it's 20 more pounds with
with the aing set than you did with the
three sets of five with the straight
sets um but you will be able to get you
know your a setting sets will be
stronger than the straight sets because
you're only doing one maximal set
whereas with the straight sets you're
repeating it twice so you're doing three
three total sets with that load okay
hope that answers your questions thanks
for watching